<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startups on Vlad Duda</title>
    <link>https://vlad-duda.com/tags/startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startups on Vlad Duda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vlad-duda.com/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from the last AI Cycle </title>
      <link>https://vlad-duda.com/blog/ai-cycle-insights-2016-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vlad-duda.com/blog/ai-cycle-insights-2016-2018/</guid>
      <description>Drawing from the AI cycle of 2016-2018, there are some insights that can be developed:&#xA;Importance of Strategic Planning: Many startups fell into the trap of assuming that AI development would be a linear process, and that increased computing power and data would naturally lead to improved AI capabilities. Infrastructure takes time to build (and time to sell to enterprises).&#xA;Need for Sustainable Business Models: The failure of the &amp;ldquo;Human-in-the-loop&amp;rdquo; approach underscores the need for sustainable business models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Winners: Incumbents, New Entrants, and Data Owners</title>
      <link>https://vlad-duda.com/blog/genai-winnners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vlad-duda.com/blog/genai-winnners/</guid>
      <description>As LLMs become more widespread, there are a few key groups of potential winners:&#xA;Incumbents with existing distribution networks: Companies like Google, Microsoft, and Amazon can layer LLMs into their existing products and services to enhance the user experience. For example, Google Search could use LLMs to provide more comprehensive and informative answers to user queries. New companies that develop specialized LLM applications: There is an opportunity for new companies to develop specialized LLM applications that are tailored to the needs of specific industries or user groups.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
